aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth,
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해
Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these brave heroes powers.
우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 내려준 용자(勇者)들
Their name is Dagwon.
그 이름은 다그온
Now, a new comrade has joined them.
그들에게 지금 새로운 동료가 가담했다
Man!
Tears of the Friendship Fusion
사나이! 눈물의 우정합체
Alien Reaper Hydron Seijin
Appears
사신 우주인 휴드론 성인
등장
Yo! Occult girl!
여, 오컬트 소녀
Did you find traces of ghosts?
왜, 유령 흔적이라도 찾았냐?
I think it's spontaneous combustion.
Spontaneous Combustion인 것 같아 (역주 : 자연 발화)
Spon... what's that?
스폰... 뭐, 뭐라고?
Spontaneous human combustion.
인체 자연 발화(人體自然發火)
A mysterious phenomenon of the human body being burnt abruptly.
사람의 몸이 갑자기 불타 버리는 괴 현상이야
Is that so?
아, 그래...
Being burnt?
'불탄다'인가...
There's no doubt.
틀림없어
We took down Phoenix Seijin before at this place.
이곳은 피닉스 성인을 해치운 곳이야
Was he brought back to life?
설마 녀석이 부활해서?
Heh! That's impossible! I must be thinking too much.
뭐, 그럴 리 없겠지 과민 반응이려나...
Well met!
안녕하시외까
I am a senior named Geki Kuroiwa from Fuun High School.
본인은 풍운 고등학교 3학년인 쿠로이와 게키라고 하오
It is a pleasure to meet you.
만나뵙게 되어 반갑소외다
Thank you for the interesting greeting!
재미있는 인사 고맙네
I am the principal, Ashiyama. Nice to meet you too.
난 교장인 아사히야마, 잘 부탁하네
I thank you greatly.
감사하외이다
To make this friendship deeper,
그럼, 벗과의 유대를 두텁게 다져야 하는 고로
please excuse me for leaving earlier.
이만 실례 하겠소외다
-Did you really get rejected six times?
-Yeah.
-정말 6번이나 퇴짜맞은 거냐?
-그래
Did you even try?
해보긴 했냐?
How stupid.
바보같구만...
Hey!
이봐!
What is that in your hands?
그게 대체 무슨 짓이지?
How dare you do that in the sacred school?
신성한 학교 안에서!
-No!
-Chair of Discipline!
-위험해!
-풍기 위원장이다!
Stop!
거기 서라!
Geki?!
게키?!
These guys are weaklings.
별거 아닌 녀석들이군
Don't worry! From now on I'll help you...
안심해라, 이제부터 매일 너를 도와주...
I told you before!
전에도 말했을 터다!
You remarkably disturb the disciplines of Sankai High School.
넌 우리 산카이 고등학교의 풍기를 현저하게 어지럽히는 존재라고 말이다
Bu- but...
하, 하지만...
Know this.
확실히 말해두지
You are annoying.
너와 함께 있자면, 성가시다
A-annoying?!
서, 성가시다고?!
Strike!
스트라이크!
What will it be this time?
그럼, 다음 가요~
Will it be shoot? Or curve?
커브일까~ 슛일까~
A man does not talk nonsense and defeat with a straight ball!
사나이는 군소리 없이 직구로 승부한다
So, come already!
자아, 어서 던져라!
Leave.
퇴장
L-leave?!
퇴, 퇴장?!
I'm sorry. I usually am good with catching bugs but...
미안하게 됐구만, 벌레 잡기는 내 특긴데...
Sheesh! Please don't disturb me!
정말! 방해하지 마세요!
D-disturb?!
바, 방해?!
Annoying!
성가시다!
Leave!
퇴장
Please don't disturb me!
방해하지 마세요!
Why?! Please explain why!
어째서냐?! 대체 왜냔 말이다!
As a Dagwon protecting the Earth,
지구를 지키는 다그온으로서
as a comrade, I just want us to practice our teamwork,
동료로서 너희들과의 팀웍을 다지려고 했는데!
but why aren't you guys understanding how I feel?
어째서 내 마음을 몰라주는 겐가?!
That's right. Teamwork is important.
확실히 팀웍은 중요하다
But that does not mean we should stick together all the time.
그렇다고 해서 평소에까지 달라붙어 있을 필요는 없어
That's right. With an ill-mannered guy like you, girls run away.
그래 그래, 너처럼 막 되 먹은 녀석이 옆에 있으면 여자애들이 도망쳐 버린다구
It's been some time since I was offered help, but I don't need a assistant.
모처럼이지만 저도 조수는 필요 없으니까요
Moreover, the teamwork of us three is already perfect!
게다가, 우리 3명의 팀웍은 확실하다구
You can see that we can combine into Liner Dagwon!
그도 그럴것이, 라이너 다그온으로 합체할 수 있으니까 말야
Co-combine?!
하, 합체?!
Yeah!
I see. A fusion!
그렇군, 합체구나!
If I can combine, I'll be able to make a friendship with all the others too!
나도 합체할 수 있다면 모두와 정을 쌓을 수 있을 거다!
These three guys can perform Chain Fusion!
이녀석들은 3명이서 중련합체!
Ryu can perform Mecha-beast Fusion with his animal comrades!
류는 동료 동물들과 기수합체!
So now... who'll I... who'll I... combine with?
그럼... 난... 대체 누구와?!
That's right! It's En! En! Where is En?!
그래! 엔이다! 엔! 엔은 어딨나?!
Become one with me!
나와 한몸이 되는거다!
Hello? Who is it?
여보쇼~ 누구냐?
En! It's me, Geki!
엔! 나다, 게키다!
Hey, wait for a moment. I got an emergency call.
아, 좀만 기다려봐 긴급 연락이 들어왔어
Yes, who is it this time?
예이, 이번엔 누구?
Dag Shadow here. I'm fighting against Killad Seijin!
여기는 다그 섀도우, 키라드 성인과 교전중!
Huh? Who are you fighting with?!
응? 누구와 싸우고 있다고?
It's Killad Seijin!
이녀석은, 키라드 성인!
Didn't we already take him down?
해치웠던 녀석 아니냐?
No time for such nonsense!
에라이, 군소리 하고 있을 때냐?!
Let's go out right now!
냉큼 출격이나 하자구!
Let's use this moment!
좋아, 이틈에!
Mecha-beast Fusion!
기수합체(機獸合體)!
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온!
Damn Killad Seijin!
키라드 성인 녀석!
No matter how you were revived, we'll take you down at once!
무슨 수로 부활했는지는 모르겠지만, 단숨에 끝장을 내주마!
You have nowhere to go, Killad Seijin!
아무래도 여기까지인 것 같군, 키라드 성인!
Now! Prepare yourself!
자, 각오하시지!
Gallon Seijin?
가론 성인?!
It can't be! A ghost?
설마, 유령?!
No need to be scared.
두려워할 것 없어
We've taken it down before.
전에 쓰러뜨린 적이 있는 상대다
Let's go!
가자!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체(重連合體)!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!
-Armor Seijin appeared too?!
-What?!
-아르마 성인까지?!
-뭐야?!
Damn you!
이놈들!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
This is the right time to combine!
지금이야말로 우리가 합체할 순간이다!
What?!
뭐야?
Only you can combine with me since we are connected by a burning friendship!
나와 합체할 수 있는 건 뜨거운 우정으로 맺어진 너 밖에 없다!
Wh-what?
무, 무슨 소리를...
Burning men's Friendship Fusion!
타올라라! 사나이의 우정합체(友情合體)!
-Hey!
-This is not right. There must've been a mistake.
-여봐!
-이상하군, 이럴리가...
Let's try this again?
그럼, 다시 한번!
Friendship Fusion!
우정~합체!
Hey, get me off!
내려줘, 얌마!
Not yet!
아직이다!
Friendship Fusion!
우정합체!
What the heck are you two doing?
너희들 지금 뭐하는거냐?!
Just a moment! As soon as we manage to combine...
기다려라! 우리가 합체만 하면...
Stop that!
작작좀 해라!
Come! Fire Jumbo!
와라! 파이어 점보!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Jet Fire Storm!제트 파이어 스톰!!
제트 파이어 스톰!
Let go of Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온을 놔라!
Did you forget that we beat you with this technique, Armor Seijin?!
이 기술에 깨졌다는 걸 잊어버린 모양이군 아르마 성인!
What?!
아니?!
What are you?!
누구냐?!
My name is Hydron.
내 이름은 휴드론
I'll make the Earth a spiritual world.
지구를 저세상(靈界)으로 만들어 주마
and you Dagwon gentlemen will help!
먼저 다그온 제군!
Begone by the malice of the aliens taken down by you guys!
네놈들에게 당한 우주인의 원념(怨念)에게 멸망당하거라!
What did you say?!
뭣이야?!
Don't make us laugh!
웃기지 마라!
Don't underestimate us!
얕보지 마라!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
Damn you!
이자식!
What the-? Our techniques are being read?
뭣이?! 싸움 방식이 읽히고 있어!
Lian!
라이안!
W-wait!
기, 기다려!
With these guts...
근성이닷!
Resistance is futile.
쓸데없는 발버둥을...
It doesn't really matter, since it isn't fun to take all of you down at once.
뭐, 상관없어 전부 해치워 버리면 재미 없으니까 말야
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
What a ridiculous guy!
정말 터무니없는 녀석이야
How did it revive the dead ones?
죽은 녀석들을 되살리다니 말야
The real problem is that they are seeing through our techniques, weapons, and war patterns!
문제는 저희들의 기술, 무기, 전투 패턴을 녀석들이 전부 간파하고 있다는 것입니다
Where... where are you?
어디에... 어디에 있는거냐?!
En! Ryu! Lian!
엔! 류! 라이안!
Hydron Seijin!
휴드론 성인!
Informing the earthlings.
지구인에게 고한다
지구인에게 고한다!
These bastards will be executed!
이녀석들을.. 처형한다!
이녀석들을 처형한다!
-Damn you!
-Wait!
-이자식!
-기다려!
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
Going to save them is unforgivable!
구하러 가는 건 용납할 수 없다!
Why is that?!
어째서냐?!
Why are you stopping me from saving them?!
어째서 녀석들을 구하러 가지 말라는 거냐?!
At this rate...
이대론...
This is a trap.
이건 함정이다
We cannot defeat the departed spirits of the aliens by on our own.
지금의 우리로선 망령 우주인들을 이길 수 없어
Hydron Seijin is provoking us, knowing that.
그걸 알고서 휴드론 성인은 도발하고 있는 거다
They are testing us if we'll come or not, knowing that we will lose.
질 거라는 것을 알고 있으면서 우리가 구하러 갈지 어떨지...
Th- that might be the case, but...
그, 그건 그럴지도 모르지만...
we can't possibly abandon En and the others!
설마 너희들, 이대로 엔 들을!
Aren't they your friends?
동료를 버릴 셈이냐?!
You guys... I am so disappointed! What is a friend? What is teamwork?
너희들... 뭐가 동료냐?! 팀웍이냐?!
I don't care anymore! I'll go by myself!
다 집어쳐! 나 혼자서라도!
You cowards...
이 겁쟁이 녀석이... (역주 : 意氣地なし -패기가 없는 사람)
Do not misjudge what's reckless and what's courageous!
무모함과 용기를 착각하지 마라!
What will the Earth become without us Dagwon?
우리 다그온이 없어지면 지구는 어떻게 되지?
We cannot make any more sacrifices!
이 이상 희생을 낼 순 없어!
I do not want to regret.
후회하고 싶진 않단 말이다...
That idiot...
저 바보녀석...
Sorry to realize that I am an idiot too.
미안하게 됐다 나도 바보인 것 같다
Illogical, but I agree with you on that.
논리적이진 않지만 저도 동감입니다
Run away... this is a trap!
도망쳐... 이건 함정이야!
At this rate...
이대론...
You came to face us, Hydron Seijin!
나왔구나, 휴드론 성인!
Welcome, Dagwon gentlemen.
어서들 오시게, 다그온 제군
I think one isn't here... Did he run away?
아무래도 한마리가 부족한 듯 한데, 도망치기라도 한 건가?
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Everyone!
얘들아!
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
We're not done yet!
아직이다!
Don't be so puffed up!
언제까지고 우쭐해하지 말라구!
By this, the Earth is now mine!
이걸로 지구는 내 손 안에 들어왔다!
More! More!
더욱! 더욱!
Now! Feel the pain! More pain! Extreme pain!
자아! 괴로워해라! 괴로워해라! 괴로워해라!
No! At this rate...
안돼! 이대론...
It's no use?
트, 틀렸나!
Your corpse will be my souvenir for the conquest of the Earth!
네놈들의 시체는 지구 정복 기념으로 삼아주마!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
What?!
아니?!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Turbo Dash!
터보 대시!
Dagwon seems to be a group of idiots!
다그온은 바보들의 집단인 모양이군!
Shut up!
닥쳐라!
Even if my body falls apart,
설사 이 몸이 부서진다 하더라도
I will save my comrades!
동료는 지켜 보이겠다!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Do not misjudge.
착각하지 마라
I thought cooperating with you guys would be more effective for saving En and the others.
너희들과 협력하는 쪽이 엔 들을 구하기 쉬울 거라고 생각했을 뿐이다
Alright! Let's combine right now!
좋았어! 지금이야말로 합체다!
What?!
뭐야?!
Four people! We four will combine!
4명이다! 우리 4명이서 합체하는 거다!
-Four?
-Combine?
-4명이서?
-합체?!
Right! We don't have any other option left!
그래! 이젠 이 수 밖에 없다!
Interesting. Agreed!
재미있군요, 좋습니다!
Right! I am all for it!
그래! 그 수에 걸겠어!
Alright, let's do this!
좋아, 해 볼까!
Alright!
좋았어!
Time to show our Dagwon Spirit!
지금이야말로 다그온의 혼을 보여줄 때다!
Super Chaining Fusion!
초중련합체(超重連合體)!
Super Liner Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온!
What the-? They combined!
아니, 합체했다!
A-awesome!
괴, 굉장해!
-It worked!
-We did it! We did it!
-해냈습니다!
-해냈다, 해냈어!
How's this? How's this?
어때, 어떠냐?!
We'll repay you severely!
지금까지의 빚, 톡톡히 갚아주겠다!
How futile!
부질없는 짓!
Are you ready?
간다!
We got this!
잡았다!
Slow!
물러!
-Coming from below!
-Leave it to me!
-아래에서 옵니다!
-맡겨두라구!
Geki Kick!
게키 킥!
How can this...
이, 이럴수가?!
Did nobody fight against that guy?
저녀석과 싸운 적이 있는 녀석은 아무도 없는거냐?!
This ends now, Hydron Seijin!
이걸로 끝이다, 휴드론 성인!
I still have one card left!
아직 비장의 카드가 남아있다!
Those guys combined too!
녀, 녀석도 합체했어!
No! Their power isn't enough!
안돼, 힘에서 밀리고 있어!
If we lose here, En and the others will be...
여기서 지면 엔 들이..!
You can count on me, if it's about strength!
힘 쓰는 거라면 내가 나설 차례지!
You won't do as you please!
니 멋대론 안된다!
Alright! The finishing blow!
좋았어! 끝장이다!
Let's go!
간다!
Finishing move! Super Liner Crush!
필살! 슈퍼! 라이너! 크러시!
It was totally awesome!
이야~ 대단했습니다!
What Super Liner Dagwon did yesterday!
어제의 슈퍼 라이너 다그온의 활약!
Oh, is that so?
아, 그래요?
He threw, and threw the oncoming enemies!
닥쳐오는 적들을 팍~ 던지고, 팍~ 던지고
It wasn't simply cool, but...
그건 정말 멋진 정도가 아니라...
If you want to talk about Dagwon, do so with my brother!
다그온 이야기라면 가쿠에게 하세요!
I am not really interested.
난 별로 흥미 없어요
Not interested?
흐, 흥미 없어요?
Hey, Kuroiwa!
여어~ 쿠로이와 군!
Are you here to make the bond of love deeper today?
오늘은 사랑의 유대을 다지기 위해?
No way! That's not it!
아악! 그런거 아니예요!
Shut up! Be quiet!
거 참 시끄럽네! 조용히 하라구요!
So- sorry!
죄, 죄송합니다
Hey, what's going on? Red face...
어머, 어떻게 된거예요? 얼굴이 새빨간데...
Could this be a symptoms of the natural phenomenon of a human?!
이거, 설마 인체 자연 현상의 조짐?!
That's not true!
아니예요;;
It wouldn't be harmful, so let me investigate!
괜찮잖아요, 좀 조사할게요
Wait!
기다려요!
Please forgive me!
좀 봐주셔요!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Demos, the demon of Space, has destroyed countless stars.
수많은 별들을 파괴한 우주의 악마 데모스
Demos has a younger sister named Anna as his twin who works as a kindergarten teacher.
그리고 데모스의 쌍둥이 여동생인
En! The kindergarten children have been taken hostage!
유치원에서 일하는 아름다운 안나 선생님
Did Demos do so?
엔! 유치원의 아이들이 인질로 잡혔다!
He's looking for Anna, the teacher!
데모스의 짓인가!?
Damn! What is it even thinking about, to look for his sister?!
녀석의 표적은 안나 선생님이다!
Calm down, En!
제길! 자기 여동생을 노리다니, 대체 무슨 속셈이냐!?
Either you keep calm, or you lose!
진정해, 엔!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! White Wings Dancing in the Wind
다음회 용자지령 다그온
바람에 흩날리는 하얀 날개
White Wings Dancing in the Wind